这是一个让我们重新开始的方法。欢迎回来，现在是该课程的第20讲
that's a let's get started again welcome
back this is now the 20th lecture of the
我们上次离开时​​的凝聚态过程我们在谈论磁性
condensed matter course when we last
left off we were talking about magnetism
我们一次要考虑一个原子的磁性，在本讲座中，我们
and we're thinking about magnetism one
atom at a time and in this lecture we're
要进行某种升级，并开始考虑其他方面的集体磁性
gonna sort of upgrade and start thinking
about collective magnetism in other
当我们有很多原子时，使用磁
words magnetism when we have lots of
atoms collective magnetism using the
当您将很多东西放在一起时，更多的是不同的主题
theme that more is different when you
put lots of things together you can get
新的和不同的物理学现在我们确实开始了一些集体
new and different physics now we did
start a little bit of a collective
上次我们谈论匈奴规则时的吸引力
magnetism last time when we were talking
about huns rules there was the when you
谈到匈奴人的规则，一个分子在hoon的作用下具有推动力，
talked about huns rules a molecule there
was the driving force by hoon's role to
尝试使分子中原子之间的自旋对齐，但也有共价键
try to align spins between atoms in a
molecule but there's also the covalent
试图阻止自对准旋转的键合物理，因此您可以
bonding physics which tried to
anti-aligned spin so you could make a
单重或共价键，而这两个事物相互竞争，
singlet or covalent bond and those two
things compete with each other and
正确获取详细信息以找出旋转将对齐还是反旋转
getting the details right to figure out
whether the spins will align or anti
对齐是一个复杂的过程，我们将要知道
aligned is sort of a complicated process
and we're going to you know brush that
完全在地毯下，然后尝试退后一步，看看
entirely under the rug and try to take a
step back and look at a model that's
会给我们带来很多我们感兴趣的物理学
going to sort of give us much of the
physics that were interested in without
在细节上陷入困境，所以我们有一些近似
getting too bogged down in the details
so we have a couple of approximation in
我们的模型，所以我们的玩具模型将没有电子跳跃，因此我们不必
our model so our toy model will have one
no electron hopping so we don't have to
担心任何种类的乐队物理学，我们都不必担心绘制紧密的绑定
worry about any sort of band physics we
don't have to worry draw a tight binding
模型，我们将不得不担心保利顺磁性所有这些
model we'd have to worry about pauli
paramagnetism all of that has been
扔掉，所以没有电子跳动，我们可以假设在每个原子上都有
thrown out so with no electron hopping
we can assume that on each atom there is
每个原子离子原子I上的每个原子上的自旋si
a spin spin si on each atom on each atom
ion atom I and I put spin in quotes
因为这个旋转我真正的意思是一个磁矩
because this spin what I really mean is
a magnetic moment that magnetic moment
可能是由于实际的电子自旋，可能是由于许多电子自旋
maybe from an actual electron spin it
may be from many electron spins it may
是轨道角动量，可能是轨道和自旋的某种组合，但
be orbital angular momentum it may be
some combination of orbital and spin but
角动量，但通常在您制作此类玩具时
an angular momentum but generally when
you sort of make these sort of toy
不管它实际上来自什么，您都称其为自旋模型，然后我们将
models you just call it spin no matter
what it's actually from and then we'll
写下哈密顿量，所以这是一个哈密顿量，三个H等于
write down the Hamiltonian so here's a
Hamiltonian three H equals and then it
有两块，第一块应该寻找
has two pieces the first piece should
look for
G mu bb点SI只是自旋与外部磁场的耦合
G mu b b dot SI that's just the coupling
of the spin to the external magnetic
领域，这是赋予我们力量磁性的术语，然后我们将添加
field this is the term that gave us
power magnetism then we're going to add
为此，我要再加上一个负号和一个1/2的小数
to it another term sum over oops i'm
going to put a minus sign and a 1/2 out
在i和j / adams的前面加上j的逗号j IJ si点s J，所以这里的术语是
front some i and j / adams i comma j of
j IJ s i dot s J so this term here is an
交互项，因此j IJ是原子ID i与j之间的交互
interaction term so j IJ is the
interaction between atom ID i and j
在原子i和j之间，我们将J IJ设为j ji，这也是
between atoms i and j and we will set J
IJ equal to j ji and this is also
有时也称为等值，在此交换中，交换常数为
sometimes called also equals and on this
exchange the exchange constant this is
大部分时间如何在凝聚态物理中使用单词交换
how the word exchange is used in
condensed matter physics most the time
并且在其中放置了1/2的事实以防止计数过度，我们希望J 1 2为
and the fact of 1/2 is put in there to
prevent over-counting we want J 1 2 to
是原子1和2之间的相互作用，但总和为s 1
be the interaction between atom 1 & 2
but in that sum there will be a term s 1
s 2在另一个术语s 2 s 1中，我们不想过多地计算它们，所以我们只是
s 2 in another term which is s 2 s 1 we
don't want to over count them so we just
将1/2放在前面，这样这个模型模型3哈密顿量3 3被称为
put a 1/2 out front ok so this model
model 3 the Hamiltonian 3 3 is known as
哈密​​顿3的3含义在之后被称为海森堡模型
the 3 meaning of the Hamiltonian 3 is
known as the Heisenberg model after
每个人最喜欢的不确定物理学家海森堡模型都经常研究
everyone's favorite uncertain physicist
Heisenberg model very frequently studied
凝聚态物理中的模型，并且很好地表示了许多磁体
model in condensed matter physics and a
very good representation of many magnets
现在我们将j IJ设置为j
now we're going to simplify this even
further simplify by setting j IJ equal
如果i和j是j个邻居的邻居，则将其设置为j，我们将其设置为
to j if i and j are neighbors by j
neighbors and we're going to set it
等于0，否则换句话说，我们将保持
equal to 0 otherwise
in other words we're just gonna keep
跟踪彼此之间最接近的自旋之间的相互作用
track of interaction between spins that
happen to be nearest neighbors with each
另外，它是一个很好的近似值，它旋转到接近
other it's a fairly good approximation
that spins on atoms that are close to
彼此见面，如果彼此相距较远，则看不见
each other see each other and if they're
farther from each other they don't see
彼此，然后我们也将简化，这是一种简化
each other and then we're also going to
simplify so this is simplification one
简化二是四现在我们将外部磁场设置为
and simplification two is four now we're
gonna set the external magnetic field to
零，我们可能稍后再放回去，所以我们的哈密顿量现在采用H的形式
zero and we may put it back in later
so our Hamiltonian now takes the form H
是IJ的负1/2和，我会这样写，所以这个符号表示I和J
is minus 1/2 sum over I J and I'll write
like this so this notation means I and J
或邻居括号符号，所以是标准的J si S，所以我们只求和
or neighbors bracket notation so a
standard J si s J so we're only summing
当我和J成为邻居时，常量只是一个常量J，在这里知道
over I and J being neighbors and the
constant is just a constant J here know
您可以从这种情况中获得一些可能性
there's a couple possibilities of what
you can get out of this sort of
哈密​​顿量，所以可能性一，让我们写下情况一，情况一是J
Hamiltonian so possibility one so let's
write down case one case one is that J
大于0在这种情况下为了使哈密顿量成为能量
is greater than 0 in which case in order
to make the energy of that Hamiltonian
相邻站点的两个自旋应尽可能小，以尝试与
as small as possible the two spins on
adjacent sites will try to align with
彼此旋转，所以当旋转对齐时，您得到的是
each other so spins align and when the
spins align what you get is
铁磁性铁磁性磁化强度不等于0
ferromagnetism ferromagnetism a
magnetization which is not equal to 0
现在，在这个哈密顿量中，旋转的方向无关紧要
now it doesn't matter in this
Hamiltonian which direction the spins
只要自旋彼此对齐，所有对齐
all align in as long as the spins are
all aligned with each other so they can
他们都指向上，他们都可以朝下，他们都可以指向
all be pointing up they can all be
pointing down they can all be pointing
现在到左边，我将把右边的东西放到相同的位置
to the left now I'll be putting the
right same you'll end up with the same
能量重要的是所有旋转
energy
what's important is all the spins
彼此对齐确定，所以这是更容易研究的案例
aligned with each other ok so this is
the easy case to study the more
要研究的复杂案例是案例二，现在J小于零，而J小于
complicated case to study is case two is
J less than zero now with J less than
邻居希望事前对齐为零
zero the neighbors want to ante align
为了使哈密顿量尽可能小或使能量尽可能小
in order to make the Hamiltonian as
small as possible or the energy as small
因此，如果我们有一个让我们在这里看到的东西，那么我们所拥有的就是
as possible so then what we have is if
we have a let's see right down here so
如果我们有一个像这样的方格，每个格上都有一个自旋
if we have like a square lattice like
this each with a spin on it if the first
旋转指向上方，然后第二个旋转将要指向
spin is pointing up
then the second spin will want to point
降低以使能量尽可能小，然后第三次
down in order to make the energy as
small as possible and then the third
旋转将指向这一点将向下指向这一点将这一点将
spin will point up this one will point
down this one point up this one will
指向下方等等，我们将交替旋转
point down and so forth and so on and
we'll get these alternating spin
结构，这就是所谓的反铁磁体，有时也称为
structures this is what's known as an
antiferromagnet or sometimes known as a
露易·纳塔尔（Louie natal）出生后就意识到了这些
nail state and he PL nail state after
Louie natal who realized that these
事物实际上存在于自然界中，那么有趣的是
things actually exist in nature and then
what's interesting about these is that
它们具有磁阶，但没有净磁化强度，
they have magnetic order magnetic order
but they have no net magnetization and
等于零，为什么它们没有很好的净磁化强度，因为
equals zero why they have no net
magnetization well because you have the
向上旋转的次数至少与向下旋转的次数相同
same number of up pointing spins as you
have down pointing spins well at least
如果我把它们画得更对齐，那看起来就像是一个平等
if I if I drew them more aligned it
would look like there was an equal
向上旋转的旋转次数向下旋转的旋转我的绘图不太好
number of up spin pointing spins is down
pointing spins my drawing isn't so good
路易斯现在知道这种情况怎么可能发生
so how is it that Louie now knew that
this sort of situation could occur well
在其中一项家庭作业中减去您要完成的作业
on one of the homework assignments less
homework assignment you're meant to
计算像这样的状态的磁化率，实际上
calculate the magnetic susceptibility of
a state like this and there's actually
您可以寻找的一些特征和磁化率
some signature and the magnetic
susceptibility that you can look for
这就是Niall在看的东西，是什么让他
which was a which was the thing that
Niall is looking at and what made him
意识到这些反铁磁状态实际上存在
realize that these anti ferromagnetic
states actually exist
但在现代时代，实际上有一种非常直接的方式来观察这种
but in the modern era there's actually a
very direct way to see this sort of
物理是要对其进行中子散射，所以让我确保你
physics which is to do neutron
scattering on it so let me make sure you
可以写下中子散射所能看到的
can write that down you can see with
neutron scattering
或中子衍射，我想我们应该称其为基本晶格
or neutron diffraction I guess we should
call it so the elementary lattice
常数可能是a，但中子实际上看到了晶格常数
constant here might be a but the
neutrons actually see a lattice constant
这么大，这就是现在的晶胞，因为如果中子是
which is this big this is the unit cell
now because the neutrons if a neutron is
随着自旋向上而来，它将自旋视为与原子不同的原子
coming in with spin up it sees an up
spin as being a different atom from a
向下旋转和中子看到向上旋转的原因与
Down spin and the reason that neutrons
see an up spin is being different from a
向下旋转是中子自身旋转并且相互作用不同
Down spin is the neutrons themselves
have spin and they interact differently
你知道如果进入的中子是自旋原子，它将相互作用
with you know if the neutron coming in
is a spin up atom it will interact
与此原子不同，因此与该原子不同，因为它们的自旋为NT
differently with this atom then with
this atom because their spins are NT
对齐，因此它会看到一个很大的质数，因此当您执行
aligned so it sees a unit cell which is
this big a prime so when you do your
中子衍射实验，您会发现它具有不同大小的晶胞
neutron diffraction experiment you will
see it a different size of the unit cell
当反铁磁性发生时，您会得到一个更大的晶胞，我应该
when antiferromagnetism occurs you get a
bigger unit cell I should actually
在这里再评论一件事，这有点微妙，但有一项作业
comment one more thing here which is a
little subtle but there's a homework
还要在这张照片上画作业，否则我应该有
assignment on it as well then in this
picture I've drawn or I should have
如果我是一个更好的艺术家，就画画。
drawn if I was a better artist up spins
down spins up spin down spin up spin
向下旋转，这是一种非常经典的思维方式，我正在思考这些
down spin and that's a very classical
way of thinking I'm thinking of these
自旋实际上是您的向量，您可以指向任何方向
spins is actually being your vectors
that you can point in any direction in
如果您在旋转方面有很大的旋转，那么您知道五个半
space if you have large spins in the
sense of spin you know five halves or
自旋s等于2或s等于9个一半或s等于3或4或类似的值
spin s equals 2 or s equals 9 halves or
s equals 3 or 4 or something like that
然后把这些图片放在这些自旋的脑海中，只是矢量
then having this picture in your head of
these spins is just being vectors that
可以指向太空中的任何方向是一张相当不错的古典图画
can point any direction in space is a
fairly good classical picture which is
相当准确，但是如果您正在谈论旋转1/2则不是很好
fairly accurate but if you're talking
about spin 1/2 then it's not so good
不再需要真正考虑量子力学了
anymore you really have to think in
terms of quantum mechanics and you can't
画出这些向上旋转的图片向上旋转向下旋转旋转1/2 T
draw these pictures of up spin down spin
up spin down spin and spin 1/2 an T for
我们的磁铁是非常复杂的野兽，想起来是不对的
our magnet is a very complicated beast
and it's not really right to think of it
这样，这更像是一种经典的直觉，适用于大型
this way this is sort of more of a
classical intuition that works for large
大旋转但是小旋转不太好，大概可以用
large spins but not so well for small
spins and that will be presumably worked
可以在家庭作业中完成，所以对此案再发表一则评论
out in a homework assignment all right
so one more comment about this this case
反铁磁性的原因是您可以拥有反铁磁性
of antiferromagnetism
is that you can have antiferromagnets
反铁磁耦合磁在三角形晶格上，然后
anti ferromagnetic coupling
mag on a triangular lattice and then
您会得到一些非常奇怪的三角形格子，让我们想象一下
you'll get something really strange
triangular lattice so let's imagine we
这里有一个三角形，三角形中有三个原子，如果第一个发生
have a triangle here three atoms in
triangle and if the first one happens to
有旋转的第二个想要在这里旋转指向
have is spin up the second one up here
wants to have spin pointing in the
与这个方向相反，所以他指向旋转，然后这个想要
opposite direction from this one so he
points spin down and then this one wants
对每个邻居都有相反的指向旋转，但是他在
to have an opposite pointing spin to
each of his neighbors but he's in
麻烦他可以指出，然后使这个家伙相反的方向，但
trouble he can point up and then make
the opposite direction of this guy but
与这个人相同的方向，否则他可以指向下方，相反
the same direction as this guy or he can
point down in which case he's opposite
这个人对这个人的方向相同，所以这个人有麻烦，他不能
this guy the same direction at this guy
so this guy's in trouble and he can't
高兴地指出任一方向，所以这就是你所说的沮丧
point happily either direction so this
is what you call frustrated frustrated
反铁磁体这几天一切都会引起挫败，所以再多
antiferromagnet everything causes
frustration these days okay so one more
这种反铁磁性或类似的物理原理
case in of this anti anti ferromagnetism
or similar physics to anti
我想提及的铁磁性是您有基础或
ferromagnetism that i want to mention is
the possibility that you have a basis or
让我们以两个原子为基础，我们两个或两个以上或更多，我是
let's let's consider a two atom basis
our two two or more or more and i'm
是晶格的基础，所以对于晶体，让我们考虑一个大原子
basis for our lattice so for a crystal
so let's consider for example a big atom
一个小原子一个大原子一个小原子大原子你会把它们变得越来越小
a small atom a big atom small atom big
atom you get them small and big out of
像这样的小四大，所以这是两个原子的基础，现在想象我们有
small four big like this so here's a two
atom basis okay now imagine that we have
反铁磁耦合，其中相邻原子要具有点
anti ferromagnetic coupling where the
neighboring atoms want to have point
它们的旋转方向相反，所以大原子指向上方，小原子指向上方
their spins in opposite directions so
the big atom say points up and the small
原子点大降低点，点向上点小，员工降低大点
atom points down big out on points up
small an employee's down big atom points
好的，我们可以继续前进这里，并获得想法，好的
up okay we can keep going here and get
the idea and okay up down
如果大原子上的自旋不等于小原子上的自旋，那么
if the spin on the big atom is not equal
to the spin on the small atom then what
我们将拥有的磁化强度将不等于零，因为您将拥有
we'll have is will have magnetization
not equal to zero because you'll have
磁化强度指向上方，那么您的磁化强度指向下方是
more magnetization pointing up then you
have magnetization pointing down is that
很清楚这是怎么工作的，即使你有反铁磁性
is that clear how that works so even
though you have anti ferromagnetic
耦合，每个相邻的自旋都想指向相反的方向，您会得到一个
coupling and each neighboring spin wants
to point in opposite direction you get a
剩余的净磁化强度，因为某些自旋大于另一个
net magnetization left over because some
of the spins are bigger than the other
自旋，这就是所谓的仙子磁力仙子磁力，它可能
spins and this is what is known as fairy
magnetism fairy magnetism and it may
看起来有点奇怪或不寻常，但实际上很常见
seem like it's it's kind of strange or
unusual but it's actually quite common
事实上，世界上最常见的磁铁是自然界中的铁3氧化物4
in fact the world's most common magnet
occurring in nature it's iron 3 oxide 4
您可以在其中找到的磁铁矿或磁铁矿
otherwise known as magnetite or
lodestone that you can you'll find in
地球有时会被拉出地球并被它磁化
the earth sometimes and it's magnetized
when you pull it out of the earth and it
会直接粘在冰箱上，实际上是由磁铁组成的
will stick to your refrigerator directly
is actually a fairy magnet it's made up
一种原子类型上大于一个原子类型上更大的矩
of more than one type of atom larger
larger moments on one type of atom
彼此之间的力矩较小，彼此反对齐，则存在
smaller moments on the other and they
anti align with each other then there's
社区中关于您是否应该称呼磁铁的争论
an argument in the community as to
whether you should call a fairy magnet a
铁磁体的子集，这是您知道人们会争论的地方
subset of a Ferro magnet and this is
where you know people will argue with
彼此直到脸色发青并且没有实际的好答案
each other till they're blue in the face
and there's no actual good answer to
这是因为人们都同时使用它，所以有人说仙女磁铁是
this because people use it both ways so
some people say that a fairy magnet is a
铁磁磁体的子集，因为它的磁化强度非零，因此会坚持
subset of a Ferro magnet because it has
nonzero magnetization it will stick to
您的冰箱，您知道这是我们认为是磁铁的特性
your refrigerator you know it's as the
property that we think of as a magnet on
另一方面，有些人认为应该保留“铁磁”一词
the other hand some people think that
the word Ferro magnet should be reserved
对于所有旋转都指向相同方向的情况，我们应该调用
for the case where all the spins point
in the same direction and we should call
这是一个神仙的磁铁，有别于所有自旋的情况
this a fairy magnet to distinguish it
from the case where all the spins are
指向同一方向，所以无论如何，您应该意识到
pointing in the same direction so anyway
you should just be aware that that's
社区中几乎没有命名冲突，所以如果
that there's that little conflict of
nomenclature in the community okay so if
我们很好，我们仍然做得不错，所以让我们继续
we're so good we're doing well still all
right so let's move on to actually maybe
你知道我会再写一遍写下海森堡哈密顿量H
you know I'll write it again well write
down the Heisenberg Hamiltonian H
海森堡再减去邻居IJ的1/2和
Heisenberg again minus 1/2 sum over
neighbors IJ
J si SJ，正如我提到的，让我们主要关注J
J si SJ and as I mentioned and let's
we're gonna sort of focus mostly on J
大于零，换句话说就是铁磁情况
greater than zero in other words the
ferromagnetic case and as I mentioned
只要这个旋转点，哈密顿量就不会在意
this Hamiltonian doesn't care which
direction the spins point as long as
不幸的是，他们现在都指向同一方向
they're all pointing in the same
direction now unfortunately most
材料并不像大多数材料实际上更喜欢旋转
materials aren't like that most
materials actually prefer the spins to
指向某个特定方向，所以这是为了表示我们
point in some particular direction and
so this is in order to represent that we
需要在汉密尔顿语中添加另一个术语，它们实际上是首先
need to add another term to the
Hamiltonian they're actually first let's
这是我在上一堂课中提到的，但我会再次提及
this is something I mentioned in the
last lecture but I'll mention it again
一件事，很明显，方向不是全部
one thing that would make it obvious
that the directions aren't all
等效的是，如果您想象有一个非常长的单位晶格，
equivalent is if you imagine having a
very long tetr-a g''l unit cell whether
你知道晶体在一个方向上很长很薄，那么你可能
you know the crystal is very long and
thin in one direction then you might
想象一下，也许旋转想沿着特别长的细线指向
imagine that maybe the spins want to
point along particular the long thin
轴可能使您可能想要向上或想要向下但不
axes maybe so you might have s wanting
to be up or s wanting to be down but not
两者之间的任何方向，所以这是您可能会期望的一种情况
any direction in between so this is sort
of a case where you might expect this
存在某种各向异性，因此为了表示我们写下一个
sort of anisotropy to exist so in order
to represent that we write down an
哈密​​尔顿DH的附加术语，我看到了Trippy或我看到了Trippy
additional term of the Hamiltonian D H
and I saw trippy or a time I saw trippy
不会叫它D我不确定哪个可能在所有原子上采用总和形式
wouldn't call it D I'm not sure which
might take the form sum over all atoms
在前面放一个减去Kappa的物体，就像在Z方向上保持不变的si
put a minus a Kappa out front that's
like some constant si in the Z Direction
平方，这为什么会偏向于具有特定的自旋
squared so why is this going to prefer
having the spin in some particular
方向很好，它想最大化SZ的大小，因此，如果SC指向
direction well it wants to maximize the
magnitude of SZ so if SC is pointing in
哈密​​顿量沿向上或向下的方向
the in the direct up direction or the
direct down direction this Hamiltonian
尽可能地小，与
is as small as possible it's as negative
as you possibly can as compared to
在SZ上光束中的s点等于零平面
having s point in the beam on the SZ
equals zero plane and where this gets
负数较少，因此这种各向异性项是我们要使用的
less negative so this kind of term this
anisotropy term is one we're going to
考虑很多，所以也许我什至会写下来，就像不停下来
consider a lot so maybe I'll even write
down like to have s up or s down not
现在侧向指向立方晶体时，您可能会想到dh
as pointing sideways now for a cubic
crystal you might expect something d-h
立方的，稍微复杂一点，可以使自旋指向
cubic which is a little more complicated
that would allow the spin to point along
任何晶体和轴，但不在晶体AXYZ之间
any of the crystal and axes but not in
between the crystal AXYZ an appropriate
哈密​​顿量可能是这样的si X到第四加si Y
Hamiltonian for that might be something
like this si X to the fourth plus si Y
到第四个加si Z到第四个，我写这个给
to the fourth plus si Z to the fourth
and the reason I wrote this to the
第四次幂是因为如果我将它们写为平方次幂，那么你只是
fourth power is it because if I wrote
them to the squared power then you just
得到sx平方加y平方加Z平方，即s平方，即
get s x squared plus y squared plus Z
squared which is just s squared and that
不在乎旋转指向哪个方向，因为它只是幅度
doesn't care which direction the spin is
pointing because it's just the magnitude
旋转，但是如果您将其写为第四至第四，这就是为什么
of the spin but if you write it as
fourth s x to the fourth that's why this
所需的力量，那么这更倾向于让它一直指向
force that's needed for it then this
prefers to have this been pointing along
晶轴之一，但不在晶轴之间，因此我们可能
one of the crystalline axes but not in
between the crystalline axes so we might
也考虑一下这一点，但主要是我们要专注于这一点
consider this one a little bit as well
but mainly we're gonna focus on this one
只需再给一个评论再发表一次，您就会知道我们在这里写的是
just one comment comment again for small
you know the what we've written here is
当我们将旋转视为经典时，这是基于我们对旋转的直觉
sort of based on our intuition for spins
when we're thinking them as classical
向量我们认为它们是小旋转的经典向量
vector we're thinking of them as
classical vectors for small spins small
这些可能很琐碎，这些术语可能很琐碎，我的意思是
spins these can be trivial these these
terms can be trivial what do I mean by
好吧，假设我尝试将其写下来旋转1/2
that well suppose I try to write this
down for a spin 1/2
记住这个自旋1/2 Polly算子Sigma Z如果是Pauli自旋矩阵
remember this spin 1/2 Polly operator
Sigma Z this the Pauli spin matrix if
您将其平方为自旋1/2，它是自旋矩阵Sigma Z的1/2
you square it for spin 1/2
it's been 1/2 the spin matrix Sigma Z
平方只是1这是一个非常无趣的运算符
squared is just 1 it's a very
uninteresting operator it's just gives
您是一个常数，因此，如果您尝试写下这样的术语以旋转1/2
you a constant so if you try to write
down a term like this for a spin 1/2
旋转它不会执行任何操作，也不会指定此bin想要的方向
spin it would do nothing it wouldn't
specify which direction this bin wants
要指出的是，如果您进行旋转-或旋转3则将是
to point in however if you did it for a
spin - or spin 3 it would it would be an
不与1平方的类似自旋矩阵变得不平凡，因此
analogous spin matrix which it does not
square to 1 it becomes non trivial so
只是要警告您不能写下来，我看到了两个B
that's just something to be warned about
you can't write down and I saw two B
足够小旋转的条件好吧，所以我们需要考虑一下
terms for small enough spins ok alright
so we need to think about this
各向异性，这将使自旋指向某些方向
anisotropy which will prefer
the spins to point in some directions
在其他方向上，我们需要考虑两种可能性
over other directions and we need to
think about two possibilities one
可能是各向异性强，另一个可能是
possibility is that the anisotropy is
strong and the other possibility is that
各向异性很弱，所以也许我会在这里写下弱点
the anisotropy is weak so maybe I'll
write down the weak case over here we
我可以寻求重复吗，我的意思是这个卡伯这个系数出现了
can I sought repeat by which I mean that
this Kappa this coefficient that occurs
各向异性项中的远小于j发生的交换常数
in the anisotropy term is much less than
the j the exchange constant that occurs
在海森堡任期中，在这种情况下，必须要做的就是首先
in the heisenberg term now in this case
what one has to do is one has to first
或最重要的是首先旋转与邻居旋转对齐
or most importantly first you spins
aligned with neighbors it spins aligned
和邻居在一起，当我首先说的时候，这是最重要的
with neighbors and when I say that first
I mean it's most important to align with
您的邻居，因为J是系统中的大能量尺度
your neighbors because J is the big
energy scale in the system once you've
与邻居对齐，然后沿着具有各向异性的直线对齐
aligned with your neighbors second you
align along a line with anisotropy with
各向异性轴，所以首先您与邻居对齐，然后每个人都决定
anisotropy axis so first you align with
your neighbors and then everyone decides
如果现在它们都与反社会的p轴对齐的话，他们的状况会更好
that they're better off if they all
align with the antisocial p axis now if
您将其与强各向异性的情况进行比较，我寻求
you compare that to the case over here
strong anisotropy strong and I sought
您的P表示这个Kappa这个各向异性常数Kappa大得多
your P meaning this kappa this
anisotropy constant Kappa is much bigger
比J大，那么首先要沿着各向异性轴对齐
than J then first you want to align
along anisotropy axis aligned along
各向异性，例如，如果我们使用的话，所有自旋都将指向上方或下方
anisotropy for example all spins will
point either up or down if we're using
上下颠簸，然后每个人都必须指向上方或下方
that up and down on a satrapy then
everyone has to point either up or down
那是你首先要做的，因为那是第二个
that's what you do first because that's
the big energy scale in the second in
系统，但是第二步，您与邻居对齐与邻居对齐
the system but then second you align
with neighbors aligned with neighbors
现在看来这是一个微不足道的区别，因为在
now this may seem like it's a trivial
distinction because at the end of the
当天的地面状态是相同的地面状态是每个人都保持一致
day the ground state is the same the
ground state is that everyone's aligned
和他们的邻居，每个人都团结一致，现在是诚实的占领轴
with their neighbors and everyone's
aligned along now be honest occupy axis
所以我为什么要为此做很多事情，这使两者有所不同
so why did I make a big deal about this
well it makes a difference the two
如果您考虑一下低能量激发，则极限会有所不同
limits make are different if you think
about what the low energy excitations
在这种情况下，低能量激发就是
are so in this case the low energy
excitations energy excitations our small
一堆旋转的角旋转，每个人或多或少地停留
angular rotations of a whole bunch of
spins that everyone stays more or less
与他们的邻居对齐，但他们只旋转了一点
aligned with their neighbors but they
rotate just a little bit from the
各向异性轴，所以这是一个小旋转小旋转
anisotropy axis so this is a small
rotations small rotations staying
与邻居对齐排列，而这里的低能量激发是
aligned aligned with neighbors whereas
over here the low energy excitations are
完全不同的低能量激发在这里
completely different low energy
excitations here the thing that's
重要的是您必须与各向异性轴保持一致，因此
important is that you have to stay
aligned with the anisotropy axis so the
低能量激发是使一些自旋翻转，但保持对齐
low energy excitation is to flip some
spin flips a spin but keep it aligned
与各向异性轴，但保持对齐，但保持在各向异性轴上
with the anisotropy axis but stay
aligned but stay on anisotropy axis okay
清楚这两者之间有什么区别吗，所以这是
is it clear what the difference is
between these two okay so this is an
这里有趣的案例，人们对此很有意思
interesting case here and it's
sufficiently interesting that people
经过大量研究，他们为此模型写下了一个有效的模型
study in a lot and they write down an
effective model for this one model which
具有以下属性，我们写一些正负i等于或等于s
has the following properties we write
some sigma i which is plus or minus s
自旋的大小，然后si是z帽中的σ
the magnitude of the spin and then s i
is as a vector is sigma i in the z hat
方向，所以基本上我们只让旋转具有完整的幅度
direction so basically we're only
letting the spin have complete magnitude
指向正上方或指向正下方的全幅
pointing exactly up or a full magnitude
pointing exactly down
然后我们可以写出非常类似于海森堡形式的哈密顿量
and then we can write out a Hamiltonian
very similar to the Heisenberg form
海森堡形式H等于还可以，所以I和J上将有负1/2的和
Heisenberg form H equals okay so
there'll be minus 1/2 sum over I and J
邻居J Sigma I Sigma J，然后加上好耦合到外部
neighbors J Sigma I Sigma J and then
plus well couple it to the external
场G mu BB Sigma I这个哈密顿量被称为缓和模型缓和
field G mu B B Sigma I this Hamiltonian
is known as the easing model easing
的模型，因为它是由伦茨（Lunz）发明的。
model because it was invented by Lenz
not easing easing was the graduate
借给这个项目的学生在1925年将其作为一个项目，他为此解决了
student who lends gave this to as a
project in 1925 and he solved this for
他的博士学位研究项目，现在我要在一维的情况下
his PhD project and what in one
dimensional case now I'm gonna make a
这个缓动模型很重要，因为这个缓动模型非常简单
big deal about this easing model because
this easing model it's extremely simple
但是它也非常复杂，很简单，因为在每个站点上只有
and yet it's also extremely complex it's
simple because on each site there's only
一个自由度，你要么不指向上方，要么指向下方
one degree of freedom and you don't
either it points up or it points down
没有其他可能性，所以这是非常简单的自由度
there's no other possibilities so it's
very simple degrees of freedom and yet
它只耦合到它的邻居，但是这个模型的物理原理是
and it couples only to its neighbor and
yet the physics of this model are
非常复杂，说这个世界可能并不夸张
extremely complex and it's probably not
an exaggeration to say the world has
从这个模型中学到了更多关于统计力学的知识
learned more about statistical mechanics
from this one model than from anything
否则我们可能会进行研究，以便在1925年通过一维轻松解决此模型
else we possibly studied so easing solve
this model in 1925 in one-dimension
在二次世界大战期间，萨加尔非常有名地设法解决了这一难题，
during world war ii on sagar very
famously managed to solve it without
二维磁场没有人同时解决过二维模型
magnetic field in two dimensions no one
has solved the model either in two
具有磁场的尺寸或三维尺寸或更高尺寸
dimensions with a magnetic field or in
three dimensions or any higher dimension
从那时起，已经有很多研究了成千上万的论文
since then so it's been a lot of study
thousands and thousands of papers have
从那时起就已经写过关于该模型的文章，我应该在最后一提
been written about this model since then
and I should mention just in the last
几年来，人们对解决这种模式进行了真正英勇的攻击
few years there's been a really valiant
assault against solving this model in
三个维度，也许几年之内可能会有解决方案
three dimensions and maybe within a few
years there will be a solution maybe not
我们可以保持乐观，但是这个模型如此有趣的原因是
we can be optimistic but the reason that
this is this model is so interesting is
因为它展示了很多有趣的物理学，尤其是关于
because it shows an awful lot of
interesting physics particularly about
即使在此模型中也只有一个自由度
phase transitions even in this this
model it only has one degree of freedom
在每个站点上的每个网站上都可以，所以我们将回到实际的
on each on each site okay so we'll come
back to the easing model actually in the
下节课，然后我们会问
next
lecture and then we will ask the
问题，我们要把它放在这里，不，我们把它放在这里，好
question we're going to put it here no
let's put it over here here okay
对于我们写下的任何模型，如果有
for any model that we write down so
we're starting here if we have a
哈密​​顿量是海森堡形式的H加各向异性形式，如果
Hamiltonian which is H of the Heisenberg
form plus the anisotropy form and if the
各向异性很强，我们可以用缓动代替组合
anisotropy is strong we can just replace
the combination with the easing
哈密​​顿量的确使整个系统对准系统将直线对准T
Hamiltonian does does the whole system
align the system align a line at T
等于零，在模型中答案是
equals zero and in the model the answer
is yes
在模型中是，但在实际磁体中不是，在实际磁体中不是，不是所有的自旋
in model yes but in real magnets no so
in real magnets not all the spins in the
系统实际上确实相互对齐，并且要了解为什么这样做，我们必须
system actually do align with each other
and to understand why this is we have to
意识到我们实际上在我们的哈密顿量中遗漏了一些重要的东西
realize that we actually left something
important out of our Hamiltonian so
让我们做一个Gedanken实验让我们假设你有一个很大的
let's do a little bit of a Gedanken
experiment let's imagine you have a big
一些磁性材料的另一块大一些磁性材料的
chunk of some magnetic material another
big chunk of some magnetic material the
这一个有一个磁化这里这个一个有一个磁化然后
this one has a magnetization here this
one has a magnetization here then you
将这两块材料很好地整合在一起
bring these two chunks of materials
together well what happens well you've
可能是当您还是个孩子的时候，当您带他们去做的时候
probably done this when you were a kid
at some point and when you bring them
在一起，您意识到他们想要像这样坐着
together you realize that they want to
sit like this they want to sit
从头到尾，因为它们具有偶极相互作用，所以磁铁想
head-to-tail because they have a dipolar
interaction and so the magnets want to
并肩而终，他们真的不想在一起
come together head to tail and they
really don't want to come together head
朝着这样的方向前进，这告诉我们，我们省略了一些重要的内容
to head like this so this is telling us
that we we left out some important piece
物理和我们遗漏的东西我们遗漏了磁能磁能
of physics and what we left out we left
out magnetic energy magnetic energy
这是思考它或偶极-偶极相互作用的一种方式
that's one way of thinking about it or
dipole-dipole interaction
在上一讲中，我提到如果您正在考虑两个旋转
in the last lecture I mentioned that if
you are thinking about two spins in a
给定原子并询问他们是否要对准偶极-偶极子
given atom and asking whether they want
to align or not the dipole-dipole
两个自旋和原子之间的相互作用很小，因此您可以忽略它
interaction between two spins and atom
is insanely small so you could ignore it
是的，但是如果您有很大一部分材料，那么您将拥有巨大的数量
that's true but if you have a big chunk
of a material you have an insanely large
每个那里的电子数量极少的偶极矩
number of electrons there each with an
insanely small amount of dipole moment
而你把它们放在一起实际上变成了一个相当大的偶极矩
and you put them all together actually
becomes a reasonably big dipole moment
而您确实需要担心这种偶极子的能量
and you do have to worry about this
dipole dipole energy another way of
想一想完全相同的物理学，如果您认为
thinking about it exactly the same
physics is to well okay if you think
关于这两张图片中的磁力线这里的磁力线
about the magnetic field lines in these
two pictures here magnetic field lines
在这张照片中看起来像这样，而在这张照片中，磁性
look kind of like this in this picture
whereas in this picture the magnetic
磁力线看起来像这样，您还记得磁能
field lines kind of look like this and
you remember that the magnetic energy
总磁能为B的积分D 3 R平方超过2微米，
total magnetic energy is integral D 3 R
of B squared over 2 mu naught and
如果您长时间对准偶极子，则总的d平方要小得多
there's the total d squared is a lot
smaller if you long align your dipoles
从头到尾，所以您通过放置偶极子来减少磁能
head to tail so you're reducing magnetic
energy by putting your dipoles
以这种方式从头到尾，因此在实际身体中实际发生的情况
head-to-tail in this way so what
actually happens in a real physical
系统，所以我们现在可以写出h等于H Heisenberg Heisenberg加h各向异性
system so we can now write h equals H
Heisenberg Heisenberg plus h anisotropy
各向异性加上我们将添加H偶极相互作用或磁性
anisotropy plus we're gonna add H
dipolar interaction or magnetic magnetic
相互作用的磁能，那么实际发生的是你得到的是你的
interaction magnetic energy then what
actually happens is you get here's your
大型系统有时系统会分解为所谓的域
big system the system will break up into
what are known as domains sometimes
所谓的老虎钳域老虎钳域
called vise domains vise domains where
some point up some point down some point
这样，他们会分解成许多小领域现在发生了什么
up like this they'll break up into many
little domains now what's going on here
在本材料的这一点上，您将在旁边旋转
at some point in this in this material
you will have up spins right next to
向下旋转，这使哈密顿语中的海森堡术语非常不愉快
down spins and that makes the Heisenberg
term in the Hamiltonian very unhappy
因为海森堡超过了汉密尔顿
because that Heisenberg out term of the
Hamilton
一旦上升旋转成为下一个上升旋转，那么这会产生一些能源成本
once the up spins to be next up spins so
there's some energy cost along that that
沿着那个过渡，这就是所谓的域墙，也许我什至会
transition along that what's what's
known as a domain wall maybe I'll even
写下这是一个过渡，称为
write that down
this is a the transition is called a
两者之间的畴壁，所以有一些海森堡能量来自旋
domain wall between the two so there's
some Heisenberg energy to have up spins
靠近畴壁上的向下旋转，但您牺牲了海森堡能量
next to down spins on the domain wall
but you sacrifice that Heisenberg energy
为了节省磁能或偶极能，
on the domain wall in order to save
magnetic energy or dipolar energy for
如果您有不同类型的各向异性，整个系统就可以了
the whole system as a whole okay if if
you had a different type of anisotropy
我寻找你的作品，例如立方各向异性域壁
and I sought your piece for example
cubic anisotropy the domain wall
结构可能看起来有所不同，您可能会有类似如下的内容
structure might look different you might
have something that looks like like this
在此指向正确的位置，它像这样向下产生
where this points up this points right
it spawns left down down like that and
这是将每种偶极子从头到尾与下一个偶极子放在一起
this was putting each dipole sort of
head to tail with the next dipole that
现在可以更好地提高能量在这种情况下发生的是
improves the energy even better now what
happens in this case is that overall the
这些磁铁之一的总磁化强度现在又为零，因为您
total magnetization of one of these
magnets is now zero again because you
上域与下域一样多，却没有
have just as many up domains as you have
down domains and you get no
完全磁化，然后您可能会知道挠头说好
magnetization at all and then you might
you know scratch your head and say well
等一下，我知道磁铁存在，你知道，那我们要怎么做
wait a second I know magnets exist and
you know so how is it we're gonna get
马格努斯是我们磁铁中的罪恶，所以现在我们必须开始思考
Magnus a ssin out of our magnets and so
now we have to start thinking a little
仔细一点，我们可以做的第一件事实际上我想我有一张幻灯片
bit carefully the first thing we can do
in actually I guess I have a slide
比再次绘制图片更好，您可以做的第一件事就是
better than drawing the pictures again
the first thing you can do is you can
想象一下，如果您在系统外部添加磁场，那么
imagine if you add a magnetic field
externally to the system the size of the
领域，我们会做出反应，布雷特，你知道如果你的磁场
domains will we react will Breit and you
know if the magnetic field that you
应用指向上，您将获得更多的向上域名，而不是向下的域名，您将获得
apply is pointing up you'll get more up
domains than down domains and you'll get
再次净磁化，但是如果您去除磁场，
a net magnetization again but still if
you take away the magnetic field the
领域回到这里的旧平衡状态，您将一无所有
domains move back to their old
equilibrium over here and you'll have no
磁化，所以我们认为这应该是费罗
magnetization so this thing that we
thought was supposed to be a Ferro
磁铁实际上是对位磁铁，它可以是非常好的功率磁铁，
magnet is in fact a para magnet it can
be a very good power magnet which gives
您会为非常小的磁铁带来很高的磁化强度
you a very high magnetization for a very
small magnet
磁场，但不幸的是，它仍然是功率磁铁，所以我们将如何获得
field but it's still unfortunately a
power magnet so how are we going to get
即使在没有施加磁场的情况下，它也具有磁性
this thing to be magnetic even in the
absence of an applied magnetic field so
制作真正磁铁的整个技巧就是60冰箱那种东西
the whole trick to making a real magnet
the kind of thing that 60 refrigerator
是找到一种方法来防止域从此配置退回
is to find a way to prevent the domains
from going back from this configuration
以此配置为例，您引用在高磁场中训练磁体的方式，
to this configuration so you quote train
a magnet in a high magnetic field so it
进入这些配置之一，其中更多的旋转
gets to one of these configurations
where there's more up spins the
公告是这张图片中的上升时刻和下降时刻，但随后您
announcements are up moments and down
moments in this picture but then you
找到一种方法来防止域移回，这就是所谓的
find a way to prevent the domains from
moving back this is what's called
钉住畴壁钉住畴壁以及您的方式
pinning pinning of domain walls pinning
domain walls and the way it's you
通常会按此顺序固定域墙，以及是否正在尝试
typically pin a domain wall is with this
order and whether one is trying to
设计一个磁铁，让您知道我们在电动机中的用途，无论您是否尝试
design a magnet for you know for our use
in electrical motors whether you trying
做一个磁铁，可以粘在冰箱上
to make a magnet that will stick to your
refrigerator where they're trying to
制作磁盘驱动器的磁铁制作优质磁铁的整个技术是
make a magnet for a magnetic disk drive
the whole art to making good magnets is
弄清楚如何使无序现象阻止磁畴移动
to figure out how to make the disorder
prevent the magnetic domains from moving
回到原始配置，磁化强度回到
back to their original configuration
where the magnetization goes back to
零好吧，为什么这种疾病会帮助您呢，所以这里是
zero okay so why is it the disorders
gonna help you alright so here's here's
应该在这里显示的图片，所以我提到这很轻松
the picture that's supposed to show us
here so this is an easing did I mention
关于放宽还是结冰的整个过程我不是说我做到了吗
the whole business about easing versus
icing I didn't say that did I did I did
我说那好吧，让我告诉你，德国人很放松，显然是这样
I say that okay so let me tell you so
easing was German and apparently the way
我认为这在德国正在减少，但随后他
it's pronounced is is is easing in
Germany I believe but then after he
完成他的论文，他去了美国，人们叫他
finished his dissertation he went to the
United States and people called him
为他的余生锦上添花，所以美国每个人都呼吁
icing for the rest of his life
and so everyone the United States calls
在欧洲，每个人都将其称为Isaac模型
it the Isaac model everyone in Europe
calls it the easing model I'll probably
永远不会弄直，但我认为称它为宽松是正确的
never get it straight but I think it is
correct to call it to call it easing
无论如何，所以这是一个缓和的磁铁，所有旋转都指向上或下
anyway so this is an easing magnet all
the spins are pointing either up or down
相互作用的高点，自旋之间的相互作用不愉快
and the highs in the interaction the
interaction between spins is unhappy
沿着域壁，我在此处绘制了所有不愉快的红色旋转
along the domain wall and I've drawn all
the unhappy spins in red here where the
向上旋转遇到向下旋转好吗，如果您从上到下进行计数
up spins meet the down spins okay and if
you count them from top to bottom
这些红色债券中有12个存在不愉快的联系
there are 12 of these red bonds where
there's an unhappy connection now in
这张图片有一个绿色的小原子，应该是缺陷
this picture there's a little green atom
there which is supposed to be a defect
如果您碰巧在域上移动，则根本不会旋转
someplace where there's no spin at all
if you happen to move over the domain
墙到这里不同的位置，这样他们就可以通过缺陷
wall to a different position over here
so they goes through the defect there's
现在只有10个红色债券而不是12个，因此如果
only 10 red bonds now not 12
so the energy actually drops if the
畴壁经历缺陷，畴壁穿过的能量较低
domain wall goes through the defect it's
a lower energy for domain walls to go
通过缺陷，以便他们想要坚持缺陷，这就是您固定域的方式
through defects so they want to stick on
the defect and that's how you pin domain
通过一次在系统中放置缺陷来使墙壁具有某种混乱
wall with a with some disorder by
putting defects in the system the once
畴壁在这种配置下，您会带走磁性
the the domain walls are in this
configuration you take away the magnetic
场，但他们不能后退，因为他们不得不放弃一些
field but then they can't move back
because they would have to give up some
能量回到原来的位置，因为它们被卡在
energy to move back to their original
position because they're stuck on the
缺陷好吧，这是一般的物理原理。
defects okay that's the general the
general physics of how it is you make a
到目前为止M都不为零的真实磁体，所以很好，所以自
real magnet which has M not equal to
zero so far so good okay so since the
您知道基本物理学确实全部包裹在
you know the fundamental physics is
really all wrapped up in the physics of
域名墙以及域名墙的移动方式值得思考
the domain wall and how the domain wall
moves it's worth thinking about the
磁畴壁更仔细一点，结果发现大多数磁铁
domain wall a little bit more carefully
and it turns out that most magnets in
自然不是各向异性强的发烧型，但有
nature are not of the eezing type where
the anisotropy is strong but there are
这种类型的各向异性很弱，所以我们必须考虑一下
this type where the anisotropy is quite
weak so we have to sort of think about
领域壁垒发生的情况不是在宽松限制内，而是在周末我
what happens in for domain walls in not
in the easing limit but in the weekend I
看到这里是极限，毫无疑问，域名墙看起来是什么
saw to be limit over here there's no
question of what a domain wall looks
就像放宽限制一样，您只是知道旋转，然后它们相遇
like for the easing limit you just have
you know up spins and then they meet
向下旋转，中间没有有趣的事情发生，但是在这里
down spins and nothing interesting
happens in between but over here where
我们有，如果您在这里旋转，而我有，我可以寻求重复
we have we can I sought repeat if you
have up spins over here and you have
向下旋转的方式请记住，为此要做的最重要的事情
down spins way over here remember that
the most important thing to do for this
一周的各向异性极限是使每个人尽可能保持一致
week anisotropy limit is to keep
everyone as aligned as possible with
他们的邻居，所以你从上旋转到下旋转的方法就是
their neighbor so the way you get from
up spin to down spin is to just slightly
将旋转旋转一次，使其与邻居相邻一点，最终使其旋转
rotate each spin just a little bit from
his neighbor and eventually make it from
向上指向下方并缓慢旋转
pointing up to pointing down with a slow
rotation okay
这就是所谓的，说超过n次旋转好吧，我没有
and this is what's known as let's say
this goes over n spins okay I didn't
画得很好，但是你就明白了，这就是所谓的砌墙
draw that very well but you get the idea
and this is what's known as a block wall
在Felix阻塞后，阻塞墙或在AL墙中钉墙猫墙
block wall or or in the AL wall nail
wall meow wall after Felix block the
同样是布洛赫（Bloch）定理的人，而路易安娜（loujain al）是意识到我们应该
same Bloch's theorem guy and loujain al
the guy who realized that we should have
反铁磁体，所以让我们尝试计算能量和
antiferromagnets so let's try to
calculate the energy and the width of
这个方块好吧，方块墙和
this block okay there is a slight
difference between a block wall and in
AL墙取决于旋转的旋转是否在
the AL wall it depends on whether the
rotation of the spin is in the plane of
这些原子或者它垂直于原子平面，就知道
of these atoms or it's transverse to the
plane of the atoms it's you know it's
这是一个细节，您可能不必担心，但是有一点点
it's a detail that you probably don't
have to worry about but there's a slight
无论如何，两者之间的差异我想我在这里画的实际上是
difference between the two at any rate I
think what I've drawn here is actually a
堵墙，让我们尝试计算该能量，因此这一能量
block wall so let's try to calculate the
energy of this so the energy in this one
尺寸图片将是II猜测值减去J si点s I加1的总和
dimensional picture it's going to be sum
over I I guess minus J si dot s I plus 1
在这里您可能会认为您可能会认为我遗漏了1/2的因数
and here you might have think you might
think that I've left out a factor of 1/2
但是我没有，因为自从我在这里，我只是在一个维度上进行总结
but but I haven't because here since I'm
I'm summing over I only in one dimension
s1 s2现在只在一个学期出现，所以我得到1/2的因数，如果
s1 s2 only occurs in one term now okay
so I got the factor of 1/2 right and if
我对齐所有对齐的自旋，然后得到II的总和，猜想我等于1到N
I align all the spins aligned I then get
a sum over I I guess I equals 1 to N of
每一个负J平方彼此对齐，并且
minus J s squared
every one is aligned with each other and
如果我每次都扭曲-对齐，那么我将其称为
if I twist it each twist
- aligned I'm then gonna let's call that
Δe等于Δe扭转自旋所付出的能量
Delta e equals Delta e the amount of
energy you pay to twist the spin from
从上到下将在I上求和等于J平方的N乘以1
top to to bottom that will be sum over I
equals 1 to N of J s squared times 1
减去theta的余弦值，所以每次您旋转一点自旋时
minus cosine of theta I so for each time
you twist the spin a little bit you have
今天就向我支付这种余弦能量是可以的，所以如果那是theta我
to pay this sort of cosine energy today
to I is is okay so if one that's theta I
旋转从一步到另一步的旋转，因此我们假设
the rotation of the spin from one step
to the next so let's assume that the
theta很小，如果我们需要从一路走到最左边
theta is small and if we need to get
from from all the way to the left all
在n次旋转中向右转的方式让我们只声明所有Thetas为n之上的PI
the way to right in n spins let's just
declare all the Thetas to be PI over n
所以我们必须旋转pi旋转n步，所以说theta是PI超过N
so we have to make a pi rotation and n
steps so we'll say theta is PI over N so
余弦theta余弦theta大约是N的1减去1/2 PI
cosine theta cosine theta is then
approximately 1 minus 1/2 PI over N
如果我将其插入此处，则平方，我将得到总共n次旋转
squared if I plug that into here I'll
get a total of n spins I'm summing over
我有J的平方，N的平方有1/2 PI，然后乘以
I have J s squared and 1/2 PI over N
squared I multiply that out I then get
PI在N上平方2 J平方，毫不奇怪，这告诉我
PI squared over 2 J s squared over N and
unsurprisingly this tells me that the
如果我旋转此能量，则能量会降低，每次旋转所需的旋转会更平滑
energy is lower if I rotate this the the
spins more smoothly that each spin wants
与他的邻居尽可能保持一致，所以如果我们只是
to be as aligned as possible with his
neighbor and so if we were only
考虑到哈密顿量的这一部分，如果旋转它们会旋转
considering this part of the Hamiltonian
the spins would if they rotated they
会无限地缓慢旋转，那样他们会很开心，但是他们
would rotate infinitely slowly and they
would be most happy that way but they
有，但这必须与各向异性能量竞争，我看到了Trippy
had but this has to compete with the
anisotropy energy and I saw trippy
能量和各向同性，希望自旋直接指向上方
energy and an isotropy which wants the
spins to be either pointing directly up
或直接下降，所以我们必须估计您要消耗多少能量
or directly down and so we have to
estimate how much energy you're going to
支付在这堵墙中既不向上也不向下的n个旋转，这是
pay to have n spins in this wall which
are neither up nor down and okay this is
一个非常粗略的近似值，但我们只能说，每次自旋不是
a rather crude approximation but we'll
just say that each spin that's not
向上和向下指点，您要支付能量K s平方好，我的意思是这个数字是
pointing up and down you pay an energy K
s squared ok I mean this this number is
可能偏离2倍或PI或类似的数值，但至少会
probably off by a factor of 2 or PI or
something like that but at least it will
给我们正确的数量级，以便块壁e的总能量
give us the order of magnitude correctly
so the total energy of the block wall-e
总的是海森堡能量PI的平方与2 J平方的平方之和
total is the sum of the Heisenberg
energy PI squared over 2 J s squared
超过n加各向异性能量和Kappa平方，则我们必须
over n plus the anisotropy energy and
Kappa s squared and then we have to
最小化等于0的总DN集，这使我们
minimize this de total DN set that equal
to 0 and that gives us
区分我们只是得到n等于pi的平方根平方2 J
differentiate that we just get n equals
square root of pi squared over 2 J over
Kappa，所以这告诉我们的是，如果各向异性
Kappa and so not surprisingly what this
is telling us is that if the anisotropy
极小，而Heisenberg耦合极强
is extremely small then and the and the
Heisenberg coupling is extremely strong
那么旋转会非常缓慢地旋转，而如果您处于另一个极限
then the spins rotate extremely slowly
whereas if you're in the other limit
各向异性大而海森堡耦合小则
where the anisotropy is large and the
Heisenberg coupling is small then the
自旋旋转的次数非常小n甚至可能直接从上到下旋转
spins rotate in a very small number n
maybe even directly from up to down in
现在，一步一步地制作出真正的磁铁，通常情况下，您可以拥有一个
one in one step now in real magnets it's
very often the case often you can have a
n大于或等于100个原子的情况，因此您可以拥有
case where n is greater than or about
equal to 100 atoms so you can have these
这些砌块墙或这些畴壁或钉子墙实际上相当
these block walls or these domain walls
or nail walls be actually quite quite
现在，如果您开始考虑，这实际上非常重要
wide now this is actually quite
important if you start thinking about
多晶材料多晶脆片晶体晶体晶体
polycrystalline material polycrystalline
crisps crystal crystalline crystalline
磁铁，所以现在我们谈论的是许多与
magnets so now we're talking about lots
of little crystal lights separated from
磁性材料彼此相互作用，如果晶体的大小轻一些
each other of magnetic material and if
the size of the crystal light a number
穿过的原子数小于该魔数，即畴壁的大小
of atoms going across is less than this
magic number the size of the domain wall
然后整个原子必须指向整个晶体光
then the whole atom the whole crystal
light has to point have its
指向一个方向的磁化只能指向一个方向
magnetization pointing in just one
direction has to point in only one
方向，您知道每个晶体我都可以指向不同的方向，但是每个
direction you know each crystal I can
point in a different direction but each
晶体光只能指向一个方向，其原因是
crystal light has to be pointed only in
one direction and the reason for this is
因为您在一个水晶灯中没有足够的空间来旋转
because you don't have enough space
within one crystal light to rotate the
从一个方向旋转到另一个方向，它太僵硬了，你不知道
spin from one direction to another it's
too stiff you can't you know the the
邻居之间的耦合太强，无法旋转
coupling between neighbors is too strong
in order to get the spins to rotate
在一个水晶光中，您可能会认为这一百个原子相当
within one crystal light and you might
think that this hundred atoms is rather
之所以小，是因为每个原子只有一个埃或两个埃，或者
small you know because each atom is only
an angstrom or two angstroms or
但如果您在这个方向上有100个原子，在另一个方向上有100个原子
something but if you have 100 atoms in
this direction 100 atoms in another
朝着另一个方向的100个原子突然间，你有一百万个原子
direction 100 atoms in another direction
all of a sudden you have a million atoms
你说的是这些水晶灯实际上可以有很多
you're talking about so these crystal
lights can actually have an awful lot of
它们中的原子，您仍然可以将它们视为
atoms in them and you can still think of
them as
微观的单个磁铁指向一个方向还可以
microscopic individual magnets pointing
in just one direction okay so so so far
太好了，我会忍受开玩笑的冲动
so good
I will resist the urge to make jokes
关于一个方向好吧，让我们想象一下，我们采取其中一个
about one direction alright okay so
let's imagine that we take one of these
水晶灯，我们将在此处应用陶瓷水晶灯，并假设
crystal lights and we are going to apply
ceramic crystal light here and suppose
它在此ray z帽子中有一个防锯齿的P轴，然后它想要指向
it has an anti saw through P axis in
this ray z hat then it wants to point
它是上下磁铁，为了争辩，我们将磁铁
it's magnet up or down and let's for the
sake of argument we'll put the magnetic
在那个方向上的磁场以及能量，然后磁矩可以
field in that direction as well the
energy and then the magnetic moment can
指向任何方向，我们喜欢晶体光的能量
be pointing in any direction we like the
energy of that crystal light is some
Enoch将会是负m点B，然后是各向异性能量
Enoch there's going to be minus m dot B
and then there's the anisotropy energy
减去Kappa MZ的平方，希望磁化强度指向
minus Kappa MZ squared this that wants
the the magnetization to point either
直接向上或直接向下，所以如果我们确定可以的话，如果
directly up or directly down so if we
decide that okay so if the angle between
M和B是Theta，那么我们可以将此能量重写为V naught减去MB余弦
M and B is Theta then we can rewrite
this energy as V naught minus M B cosine
theta减去Kappa M平方余弦平方theta，实际上我们甚至可以
theta minus Kappa M squared cosine
squared theta and in fact we might even
令x等于余弦theta，那么我们得到的是一个零的负M的二次轴
let x equals cosine theta and then what
we have is a quadratic ax naught minus M
BX减去K M平方x平方，我们可以画出这个东西啊，我
B X minus Kappa M squared x squared and
we can plot this thing ah oops I'm
房间快要用完了吗，我们可以将其绘制为theta的函数
running out of room aren't I okay we can
plot this thing as a function of theta
或作为X的函数，所以这就是能量，让我们从B开始
or as a function of X so this is the
energy and let's start in the case of B
等于零，所以您拥有晶体光和零磁场，并且您的
equals zero so you have your crystal
light and zero magnetic field and your
此处的能量x等于减一减一，此处的能量x等于加
energy over here is x equals minus one
minus one and over here is x equals plus
我们这里拥有的是x等于减1是theta等于pi x等于
one what we have here is so x equals
minus one is theta equals pi x equals
加一是theta等于零，所以这就是磁化强度
plus one is theta equals zero so this
over here is the magnetization pointing
向下和上方，我们的晶体光的磁化指向上方
down and over here we have the crystal
light with the magnetization pointing up
能量是二次方像这样所以有两个稳定的
and the energy is quadratic looks kind
of like this so there's two stable
点这里的稳定点是使磁化强度指向下方
points the stable point here is to have
the magnetization pointing down in the
这里的稳定点是使磁化指向上方，这非常重要
stable point here is to have the
magnetization pointing up and it's much
让磁化指向任何其他方向不太高兴，这是
less happy to have the magnetization
pointing in any other direction this is
不足为奇，因为它是各向异性轴想要夜晚
not surprising because it's the
anisotropy axis wants the the night
磁化点向上或向下都好现在让我们添加一个非零磁场
ization point either up or down okay
now let's add a non zero magnetic field
好吧，现在让我们让V等于零或小于零但不等于零
okay so now we'll let V naught equal to
zero or be small but not equal to zero
等于零，所以现在又是收获，我们有一个抛物线，它仍然是二次方
equals zero so now it's Reap lot again
we have a parabola it's still quadratic
但是抛物线现在因为能量中的线性项而移动了
but the parabola is now shifted because
of the linear term in that in the energy
这样抛物线的峰值将不再位于中心
so that the peak of the parabola will
not be in the center anymore will be
偏心，所以我们将得到一个像这样的抛物线，在这里我们再次
off-center so we'll get a parabola looks
like this and again over here what we
即使磁场指向上方，磁化强度仍指向下方
have is magnetization pointing down even
though the magnetic field is pointing up
在这里，我们的磁化指向上方，磁铁和
and here we have the magnetization
pointing up and the magnet and the
磁场指向上方，因此此点具有磁化指向
magnetic field pointing up so this point
here having the magnetization pointing
在相同的磁场方向上，这绝对是稳定的最小值
in the same direction of magnetic field
this is definitely the stable minimum
而这里的这一点是亚稳态的，以便从
whereas this point over here is
metastable in order to get from the
磁化的亚稳态情况指向与
metastable case of the magnetization
pointing in the opposite direction as a
磁场以确保能够下降到此处
magnetic field in order to secure to get
down to here where it would rather be it
必须克服激活障碍，这意味着您必须承担所有
has to get over this activation barrier
and this means you have to take all of
您的原子中可能含有一百万个这些原子，并以某种方式将它们全部翻转
your atoms with maybe a million of these
atoms and somehow flip them all over
同时进行热或量子隧穿，这是一个过程
simultaneously either thermally or by a
quantum tunneling and that's a process
这是如此的困难，以至于在低温下它可能永远不会发生，所以
that's so difficult that at low
temperature it may never happen so the
这些你可以拥有这些磁铁的小晶体在
these you can have these little crystals
of magnets have their magnetic in the
现在方向错误，让我们再加一点磁场
wrong direction now let's turn up the
magnetic field a little bit more so now
我们又有一个大的磁场B又有一个抛物线
we have a large magnetic field large B
again we have a parabola but the met but
抛物线的最大值一直移到左侧
the maximum of the parabola has been
shifted all the way off to the left this
X是负1，这是x等于加1，抛物线的最大值超过了
X is minus 1 this is x equals plus 1 and
the maximum of the parabola is way over
在这里离开情节，所以这一点在这里，磁化指向
here off the plot and so this point here
with the magnetization pointing in the
磁场的相反方向限制现在变得不稳定，而
opposite direction limit of the magnetic
field is now unstable and whereas this
此处的唯一点是磁化强度指向相同的唯一稳定点
point over here is the only stable point
with the magnetization pointing the same
磁场方向也可以，所以如果磁场足够大
direction as a magnetic field ok so if
the magnetic field is turned up enough
然后您可以将所有Magna zatia翻转过来，指向
then you can flip over all of the Magna
zatia's to point in the direction of the
磁场很清楚是如何运作的，所以这是你的照片
magnetic field is that clear how that
works ok so this is a picture you've
之前看到的是所谓的硬铁磁体的图片，也许我
seen before it's a picture of a
so-called hard Ferro magnet maybe I
甚至应该写下这个词，因为它经常用硬铁磁性
should even write that word down because
it's used often hard Ferro magnet hard
铁磁体是当您实际上B中的M不等于0时，
Ferro magnet is when you actually have M
not equal to 0 in B equals 0 and the way
你会得到坚硬的铁磁体，我们知道了如何使你变得坚硬
you get hard ferromagnets you know we
explained that how you could get hard
通过固定畴壁来获得铁磁体，但您也可以考虑
ferromagnets by pinning the domain walls
but you can also think about getting
含有很多微晶的硬铁​​磁体，您需要
hard ferromagnets from having lots of
little crystallites and they you need to
为了推动微晶翻转，你必须给它们一些
in order to push the crystallites to
flip over you have to give them some
矫顽场，你必须给他们有限的磁场
coercive field you have to give them a
finite magnetic field in the wrong
方向和相反的方向，以使它们全部翻转
direction and in the opposite direction
to get them to all flip over if you just
在不翻转的方向上给它一个小的磁场
give it a small magnetic field in the
other direction they don't flip over and
如果您考虑一下，这就是这些磁铁的磁滞回线的原因
this is what gives these magnets
hysteresis loops now if you think about
一秒钟，您意识到将图片固定在
it for a second you realize that this
picture of pinning domain walls in a
水晶磁铁，此图片显示在哪里该图片在哪里
crystalline magnet this picture oops
where to go this picture here where the
畴壁卡在其位置，因为它具有能量激活
domain wall is stuck on its position
because it has an energy activation
离开该位置的障碍，在此位置原子使它降低
barrier to get off of that that position
here where the atom gives it a lower
能量，如果畴壁达到那个点，则与
energy if the domain wall goes to that
that point it's extremely similar to
我们在这里拥有的所有这些小水晶灯唯一的区别
what we have here with all these little
crystal lights the only difference here
就是您可以认为，在水晶灯的作用下，畴壁总是
is that you can think with the crystal
lights the domain walls are always
在微晶之间，如果您想以某种方式思考
between the crystallites if you want to
think of it that way that some crystal
灯会指向某些方向
lights will point in one direction in
some
将指向另一个方向并移动域墙，您必须翻转
will point in the other direction and to
move the domain wall you have to flip
多于一个的微晶，所以它的物理原理极其相似
over one more crystallite so it's
extremely similar physics the moral of
故事是，为了得到真正的磁铁，硬铁磁铁会以某种方式
the story is that in order to get a real
magnet a hard Ferro magnet somehow or
其他您是否必须使系统混乱
other you have to have disorder in your
system whether it's making the system
进入小小的水晶灯或放置障碍物，它会固定
into small little crystal lights or
putting disorder and it's going to pin
域名墙的位置还可以，今天就完成了
the position of the domain walls okay
that's all for today I will see you is
是星期四星期四，是的，星期四好，周末愉快
it Thursday Thursday yeah Thursday okay
have a good weekend
[掌声]
[Applause]